Ferrari is a history, drama film directed by Michael Mann.
Set during the summer of 1957.
Ex-racecar driver, Enzo Ferrari, is in crisis.
Bankruptcy stalks the company he and his wife, Laura,
built from nothing ten years earlier.
Their tempestuous marriage struggles with the mourning for
one son and the acknowledgement of another.
Enzo Ferrari, played by Adam Driver.
Laura Ferrari, played by Penélope Cruz.
Lina Lardi, played by Shailene Woodley.
Alfonso de Portago, played by Gabriel Leone.
Linda Christian, played by Sarah Gadon.
Peter Collins, played by Jack O'Connell.
Ferrari is a 2023 American biographical sports drama film directed
by Michael Mann and written by Troy Kennedy Martin.
Based on the 1991 biography Enzo Ferrari: The Man, the Cars, the Races, the Machine by motorsport journalist Brock Yates, the film follows the personal and professional struggles
of Enzo Ferrari, the Italian founder of the car manufacturer Ferrari, during the summer of 1957 as Scuderia Ferrari prepares to compete in the 1957 Mille Miglia.
Adam Driver portrays the titular subject, and Penélope Cruz, Shailene Woodley, Sarah
Gadon, Gabriel Leone, Jack O'Connell, and Patrick Dempsey co-star.
Ferrari was selected to compete for the Golden Lion at the 80th Venice
International Film Festival, premiering on August 31, 2023.
The film was originally set to premiere on the streaming service Showtime, but it was
eventually released in the United States theatrically on December 25, 2023, by Neon.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was named one
of the top 10 films of 2023 by the National Board of Review.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing only $43
million worldwide against a $95 million budget.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
biography, based on true story, racing, 1950s.
The tone is emotional.